Andi Miller

West View Cottage Phone: 07837 429193

Upperton Email: andi@andimiller.net Petworth IRC: Sylnai@irc.freenode.net West Sussex Homepage: andimiller.net

GU28 9BE

Portfolio: https://github.com/andimiller/

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

LANGUAGES

Scala My main day to day language at DataSift, both in a Java interoperable style, and in a functional style.

Java I am familiar with using Java in large teams, and used it for multiple projects at DataSift. С Covered during my degree, used it for university work and personal projects, wrote patches for OpenSIPS and Asterisk while at Gradwell.

C#Learnt while at College, used for many personal projects including a network monitor, a few small games, some of which had network capabilities.

PHP Maintained old PHP webapps at Gradwell and DataSift, using it for some of my own sites

Python Worked on Jokosher and PiTiVi as part of the Google Summer of Code, used for many personal projects including pizza-auth, a large scale LDAP user management tool for EVE Online alliances.

Andi Miller 2

TECHNOLOGIES

Large Stream Processing Have real world experience building scalable stream processing systems with tech-

nologies including Kafka, zeromq and redis at DataSift.

Big Data I also have experience with Hadoop and ELK for storing and indexing large

latasets.

Parallel Programming I enjoy writing parallel processing jobs, and have used python, Hadoop and spark

for it.

Scalability I enjoy architecting systems which can scale, this was our primary feature when

building systems at DataSift.

Language Development

Metrics

Have implemented domain specific languages using both ANTLR and flex/yacc. A habit I got into at DataSift, I tend to add metrics to everything I write and aggregate them in graphite, grafana or riemann, I really like having a central

dashboard with full statistics available on deployed applications.

Network Protocols Have implemented a variety of protocols in many languages, including IRC,

HTTP, FTP and NTP.

Server Admin Have experience with managing many types of servers, including various Linux

and BSD distributions, and Windows Server. Also maintain my own virtual and physical servers for my own projects and online game groups I play with.

Typesetting Writing up many project reports, and this CV in LATEX. I have also written a

couple of LATEX to HTML converters.

UNIX and Linux After using *NIX systems for many years, I am more than competent at admin-

istering systems running a *NIX-like Operating System.

Version Control When coding I've used lots of Version Control systems, including SVN, Git,

Mercurial and Bazaar.

Virtualization I maintain a set of Virtual Machines for testing personal projects, and have

experience administering KVM and OpenVZ clusters.

Web Development I maintain multiple websites in my spare time, and am familiar with modern web

development practices including HTML5, CSS, Websockets and Scala.js.

Andi Miller 3

EDUCATION

B.Eng. Software Engineering, Aberystwyth University, 2009 - 2013.

2:1, just below a First

Averaged over 70% in core Programming modules.

did Artificial Intelligence modules

Alton College, Alton, Surrey 2006 - 2008

A-Levels: Further Maths - C, Maths - A, Physics - B, Computing - A.

AS-Level: Electronics - B.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer, DataSift (MediaSift Ltd.), June 2013 - Present

Worked in an agile team developing Scala microservices.

Practiced agile test driven development in a team.

Developed and maintained an in-house Domain Specific Language for transforming JSON

Maintained client-facing API libraries and their documentation

VoIP Engineer, Gradwell dot com Limited, June 2011 to July 2012.

Maintained and made improvements to one of the largest award-winning Open Source VoIP stacks in the UK

Regularly worked with both Support and System Administration departments.

Worked in a variety of languages, including Perl, C, Python and Ruby.

Worked in an engineering team using Jira and Mercurial.

Freelance Coder (Google Summer of Code), Google, Summer 2010.

Worked to a strict deadline

Integrated into the community

Learned many new technologies, including:

DBus

GTK

Bazaar

References

Available on request.

Last updated: November 10, 2015 http://andimiller.net/